<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guowei Lv</title>
    <link>http://lvguowei.me/categories/fragrance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Guowei Lv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://lvguowei.me/categories/fragrance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Choco Musk by Al Rehab</title>
      <link>http://lvguowei.me/post/choco-musk-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 21:23:38 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lvguowei.me/post/choco-musk-review/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://lvguowei.me/img/choco-musk.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is my first perfume oil/attar, I have to say I am quite impressed by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I adore oriental culture. I prefer sophiscation over simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like dark, dense, rich scent, which shows marks of history. And I am very bored with the
western happy and fresh mall scents, yet not satisfied by the so call &amp;ldquo;oriental accord&amp;rdquo; interpreted by western perfumery.
So I went online and searched &amp;ldquo;middle east perfume&amp;rdquo;, and what I found truely suprised me. They are so cheap! I mean extremely cheap,
comparing to the price tags we are used to in the western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I randomly picked a popular one, which is this choco musk by al rehab. Upon opening the bottle I know this is not bad.
It is a smell that is unique, something makes you remember it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is a gourmand. No question about that. Chocolate, milk, caramel, vanilla, you name it.
But that is not all, there is also this spice mixed in it. Some will say it smells a bit plastic, well I know saffron can sometimes do that to your nose,
so I suspect it is saffron but I am not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It becomes darker with time, which is exactly what I like about it. There is also an earthy dry smell in the dry down, which I guess might be pachouli,
cause I experienced the same in the dry down in Angle Men by Theirry Mugler, which is a similar kind of chocolaty scent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It smells distinctly arabic, I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what causes that, but you know it comes from the east.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one sentence, it smells like dark chocolate cookie with a bit of oriental spice and a drop of milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a 6 x 6ml box, which will probably last me a life time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projection and longevity are decent, not beast mode though, which is a good thing for me. Just one or two dabs will last you a whole day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This perfume oil makes me question the western perfumery industry, I have 60 - 70 euro big brand bottles, Chanel, Dior, Hermes. But how much
is spent on the commercial ads, models, campaigns, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But I found the middle east perfumery more honest and humble.
They do it like commodity not luxury, which I respect a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>